Andrew Jennings

afjennings@gmail.com • https://www.afjennings.com • Philadelphia, PA

Summary

I am a web developer with more than ten years of experience creating attractive and easy-to-use applications. My experience in systems administration means that I can design and debug an application from top to bottom and deploy it on local hardware or in the cloud

Skills

Programming Languages

- Proficient with PHP, Python, JavaScript, SQL
- Tinkered with C#, Ruby, Java, Go

Software and Frameworks

• Angular, Vue, Laravel, Symfony, Django, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, .Net MVC, jQuery, Bootstrap

IT Systems

• Docker, AWS, Apache and nginx, Linux deployments and administration

Experience

Freelance Work - Philadelphia, PA

Full-Stack Software Developer, Feb 2019 - Present

Updating and creating applications for various clients, mostly using Laravel or Symfony with Vue.js.

- Top Rated Plus on Upwork
- Satisfied Clients by developing apps from scratch and updating existing custom applications

University of Pennsylvania School of Arts and Sciences - Philadelphia, PA

Senior Application Developer, Sept. 2012 - Feb. 2019

Developed web applications used by the faculty, staff and students of the School of Arts and Sciences

- Penn Reviewer
 - Enabled the submission and grading of assignments for the Creative Writing program
 - ♦ Symfony 2 backend API with Angular 4 frontend
 - Gathered requirements and create wireframes; Coded application with two other developers;
- SAS Timesheets
 - ♦ Replaced the use of paper timesheets by employees of the school
 - ♦ Symfony2 application with jQuery, Bootstrap and Oracle
 - ♦ Designed and implemented timesheet-entry page to allow users to enter work hours; Created commands to notify users via email of missed hours, incorrect entries, and unexpected changes;

• Other projects included a database-to-web-app conversion for the fund-raising office to track endowed chairs, an email notifier to assist with o365 account-status changes, and a system that transformed Excel files to a suitable format and submitted them for financial journaling.

Azavea - Philadelphia, PA

Software Developer, May 2008 - Sept. 2012

Developed geospatial web applications to help people discover their elected representatives and engage in the political process

- The Cicero API
 - ♦ Web service provided accurate listings of elected officials based on district geography rather than zip code
 - ◆ Maintained version 2, which used C# and ESRI's ArcIMS maps; Designed and assisted in coding version 3 REST API using Django, PostGIS and MapServer;
- The Committee of 70's Online Citizen's Guide
 - ♦ Allowed users to view their current elected officials and find their polling place
 - ♦ C# web application using the .Net MVC framework
- DistrictBuilder
 - ◆ An open-source application that allowed users to draw their own Congressional districts and share their redistricting plans with elected officials and other mappers
 - ♦ Django web framework with PostGIS data
- DevOps work
 - ◆ Installed and maintained VMWare servers and clients; Assisted with move to central SAN; Developed methods to create AMIs, deploy to EC2 instances, and monitor servers;

PENN Medicine Office of Development - Philadelphia, PA

IT Support Specialist, Oct 2006 - May 2008 Office Systems Coordinator, April 2005 - Oct 2006

• I was primary desktop support and systems administrator for health system fund-raising office of 90

Sony Computer Entertainment America - Foster City, CA

Quality Assurance Analyst, Mar 2001 - Mar 2002

• Discovered and documented errors in PlayStation 2 software

Education

Master of Computer and Information Technology

Fall 2005 - Spring 2008 University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor of Arts, Journalism

Fall 1995 - Fall 1999

The Pennsylvania State University, State College, PA